# **JATIN JAWA**

# Finance Professional

Experienced and dedicated MBA Finance professional carrying five years of working experience into IT Sector, professional service firm and real estate industry. Possesses strong problem solving and analytical skills that help me work efficiently and independently. Experienced into Report to Record, invoicing and Financial Reporting.

# **Work History**

#### 2022-03 -2022-10

### **Advance Record to Report Analyst**

Ernst and young, Gurgaon

- Preparation of Balance sheet reconciliations for different US Business units.
- Aligned all financial activities with GAAP regulations and standards.
- Preparation of monthly and quarterly reconciliation Schedule.
- Preparation monthly, quarterly and annual profit and loss statements and balance sheet.
- Perform day to day financial transaction including, classifying, verifying, computing, posting and recording intercompany account receivable data and reconciled monthly totals.
- Processing of Accruals for US entities with multiple trading partner based on current AR statement.
- Responsible For preparing and reviewing AP ageing.
- Well versed with Mechanism of PO and NON PO invoices.
- Reconcile various accounts, correcting any variances.
- Posting of Journal entries of goods and invoice receipts on Monthly Basis.
- Assisted with month end and year end closing and reporting.

#### 2021-09 -2022-02

# Senior Finance and Accounting Analyst

Price waterhouse cooper, Gurgaon

- Prepared Monthly/quarterly balance sheet reconciliations to obtain accurate picture of organization's financial situation.
- Reconciled accounts, managed audits and updated financial records with remarkable accuracy.
- Created detailed expense reports to facilitate reimbursement for business expenses incurred.
- Strengthened financial operations by conducting bank reconciliations and financial reporting.
- Tracked financial progress by creating quarterly and yearly balance sheets.
- Reconciled account information and reported figures in general ledger by comparing to bank account statement each month.

### 2021-01 -2021-09

# **Accounting Analyst**

Jones Lana Lasalle, gurgaon

Handled day to day Accounting process to drive

### Contact

#### **Address**

Faridabad, India 121002

#### **Phone**

7048916768

#### E-mail

jawajatin96@gmail.com

### **Skills**

Variance Analysis
MS Excel
Reconciliations
Journal entries
Month end closing
Financial statements

### Software

Vertex
Oracle
Peoplesoft
SAP
Workday
Account reconciliation
Manager(ARM)
Precision Plus

# **Accomplishments**

- Secured Merit in 12th standard with 92% marks.
- Secured first division in Bcom.
- Secured Second Position in School Math's Olympiad.
- Won player of the tournament award working with Ernst and young.
- Part of corporate cricket Team of Genpact.
- Was part of corporate cricket team of EY.
- Worked as a Member of NSS Society.
- Worked as a Member of Commercium Society.
- Volunteer in ADAR (Anti Drug and Anti Ragging Campaign of Leaders for

Tomorrow Society).

#### financial accuracy.

- Prepared monthly, quarterly balance sheet reconciliations.
- Developed monthly, quarterly and annual profit and loss statements and balance sheet.
- Recorded deposits, reconciled monthly bank accounts and tracked expenses.
- Documented cash, credit, fixed assets, accrued expenses, and line of credit transactions.
- Handled day-to-day accounting processes to drive financial accuracy.
- Matched purchase orders with invoices and recorded necessary information.
- Reported financial data and updated financial records in ledgers and journals.
- Reviewed financial reports and streamlined operations to increase productivity and company profits.
- Gathered financial information, prepared documents, and closed books.
- Created detailed expense reports to facilitate reimbursement for business expenses incurred.
- Gathered, evaluated and summarized account data in detailed financial reports.
- Generated invoices upon receipt of billing information and tracked collection progress.

# Finance and Accounting Associate

Accenture, Gurgaon

- Preparation of All balance sheet reconciliations.
- Reported financial data and updated financial records in ledgers and journals.
- Posting of Journal Entities on Monthly and quarterly basis.
- Effectively communicated with clients about payment needs and kept updated, detailed and accurate ledgers.
- Analyzing of client current situation based on the current resources, assets, liabilities, investment, cash inflow, cash outflow, insurance coverage, retirement plans.
- Matched purchase orders with invoices and recorded necessary information.
- Reconciled account information and reported figures in general ledger by comparing to bank account statement each month.
- Strengthened financial operations by conducting bank reconciliations and financial reporting.
- Implemented policies for SOX compliance and GAAP requirements when compiling financial statements and disclosures.
- Analyzed and interpreted accounting information to develop company expense budget.
- Prepared monthly reconciliation of bank accounts and took corrective actions on deviations.
- Oversaw accounts payable and receivable transactions.
- Prepared quarterly revenue, expense and performance reports.
- Maintained journal entries to track and analyze credit and debit transactions.
- Developed strategic plans for day-to-day financial operations.
- Prepared internal and regulatory financial reports, balance sheets and income statements.
- Checked payroll, vendor payments, commissions

### 2019-05 -2020-09

and other accounting disbursements for accuracy and compliance.

 Prepared cash flow projections, cost analysis and monthly, quarterly and annual reports.

#### 2017-09 -2019-03

# Finance & Accounting Associate

Genpact, Gurgaon

- Prepared monthly reconciliation of bank accounts and took corrective actions on deviations.
- Preparation of journal entries and performed accounting on accrual basis.
- Reconciled account information and reported figures in general ledger by comparing to bank account statement each month.
- Developed monthly, quarterly and annual profit and loss statement.
- Collected and reported monthly expense variances and explanations.
- Assessed data and information to verify entry, calculation, and billing code accuracy.
- Organized budget documentation and tracked expenses to maintain tight business controls.
- Tracked financial progress by creating quarterly and yearly balance sheets.
- Presented audit findings to accounting manager after reviewing results and paperwork.
- Reconciled accounts, managed audits and updated financial records with remarkable accuracy.

MBA: Financial Management

 Maintained account accuracy by reviewing and reconciling checks monthly.

### **Education**

2021-01 -

2023-02	
	NMIMS - Mumbai
2014-06 - 2017-05	B.com : Finance
	Delhi University - Delhi 71%
2013-04 - 2014-03	12th: Commerce
	A.V.N - Faridabad
	92%
2011-04 - 2012-03	10th: General Studies
	A.V.N - Faridabad

7.2CGPA